VML External Privacy Policy
===========================

**Date Last Updated 31/12/2023**

**Introduction**

This Privacy Policy contains important information about how we use your personal information. We respect the privacy of individuals who interact with our business and where you choose to provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner with that information.  
In this privacy policy, references “us”, “we”, “VML” or “our”, and are all references to VML.

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about any aspect of this policy or how VML handles your information please email our privacy team at [dpo@vml.com](mailto:dpo@vml.com)

**What information do we collect?**

We collect personal information from you in several ways; you may share information with us, or we may collect it using other means. In this section we explain the different ways we collect personal information from you and some ways in which that information will be used.

_**Requesting information from us and responding to your queries**_

We process contact information such as name, email address, telephone number or postal address, preferences, and other declared personal information about you when you provide it to us. For example, when you fill out online forms, subscribing to our services, call, or text us, enquire about our products and services.

_**Interacting with us via Social Media Channels**_

We process information relating to you when you interact with us through social media platforms such as Linkedin or Facebook.

_**Registering for and attending our events, seminars, or conferences**_

If you choose to attend one our events, we will ask for your contact information to provide you with details of the event and manage your attendance. For in-person events, we may ask you to provide us with accessibility information, if appropriate

_**Updating you on developments and initiatives**_

We may process your contact information to keep you updated on updates and developments in our business.

_**Interacting with our website**_

When you visit our website we may collect details of your website visit, including name, email, phone number, IP address (a unique identifier for your computer or other device), website URL and mobile device ID. Our website also uses cookies please see our cookie policy here for [details](https://www.vml.com/cookie-policy).

**_Applying for a job at_ _VML_**

We process information provided by you in relation to submitting a job application to VML (this may include sensitive personal information for example ethnic origin). Please see our Recruitment Privacy Policy [here](https://www.vml.com/recruitment-privacy-policy) for further information.

_**Visiting our offices**_

We may collect information such as contact information (including name, email address, telephone number) and CCTV footage in respect to your visit to our office address.

**_Interacting with us as a client of_ _VML_**

When interacting with us as a client, we process information we may receive from you or from others in relation to our provision of services to our clients. Please see our Client Privacy Policy [here](https://www.vml.com/client-privacy-policy) for further information.

**_Interacting with us as a supplier or partner to_ _VML_**

We process information in relation to you as an individual if you provide services to us (or if you work for a company that provides services to us). Please see our Supplier Privacy Policy [here](https://www.vml.com/suppliers-privacy-policy) for further information.

**How do we use it?**

We will use your personal information in the following ways. We are also required by law to state a “legal basis for processing”, i.e., to tell you on what grounds we are allowed to use your information, and this is also set out below:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **How we will use your personal information** | **Our legal basis for processing** |
| To provide or respond to you, with information that you have requested, e.g., this could relate to a newsletter, bulletin, an invitation for an event, your interaction with us on social media | Consent – we only use your personal information for this purpose if you have asked us to do so. You can withdraw your consent at any time. |
| To keep you updated with developments and initiatives at VML, its affiliates or partners | Our legitimate interests – we use your information to provide you news and updates on VML, its affiliates or partners. You will always have the opportunity to opt-out in each correspondence. |
| To process your registration for and attendance at events, seminars, conferences, and meetings with VML, its affiliates or partners | Our legitimate interests – we use your information to book you on to the requested events and to send confirmation to you and the event organiser. |
| To respond to specific queries you may raise regarding VML, its affiliates and partners | Consent – we only use your personal information for this purpose if you have asked us to do so. You can withdraw your consent at any time. |
| To provide you with better ways of accessing information from this website | Consent – we only use your personal information for this purpose if you have consented for us to do so. You can withdraw your consent at any time. |
| To process and consider your job application. | Our legitimate interests – we use your personal information to assess your job application, update you on its status and keep you informed of other opportunities, if you have asked us to, via the methods you have selected. |
| To manage your visit to the office | Our legitimate interests or any other purposes required by law such as for example, compliance with fire protection regulations. |

For how we use your information that is collected using cookies and similar technologies, please review our cookie policy [here](https://www.vml.com/cookie-policy).  

**Do we pass your information to third parties?**

We may send your personal information to other VML and WPP group companies, affiliates and third parties to help us process your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy. Further details of our group companies can be found [here.](https://www.wpp.com/Contacts#tab-companies)

We may disclose your personal information if we or any of our assets are the subject of a sale or similar corporate transaction. We will ensure that the third parties who receive your personal information are required to keep it confidential.

We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual unlawful or otherwise prohibited activities, including, but not limited to, fraud.

**Where do we send your information?**

We are a global company and therefore we may transfer your personal information to countries around the world including the US and other countries outside of the UK and Europe. We will, where the country to which your data is transferred has not been found to provide an adequate level of protection, put in place appropriate safeguards (we use standard contractual clauses) to ensure your information is protected.

**How long do we keep your information?**

We only keep your personal information for as long as we need to, to be able to use it for the reasons given in this privacy policy, and for as long as we are required to keep it by law.

**Third Party Websites**

Our website links to third party sites which we do not operate or endorse. These websites may use cookies and collect your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites and we are not responsible for third party websites.

**How do we protect your information?**

We take appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure that your personal information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

**Children’s Privacy**

This website is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from or about any person under the age of 16. If you are under 16 years old and wish to ask a question or use this site in any way which requires you to submit your personal information, please get your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

**Your rights**

You are entitled to ask:

1\. for a copy of the personal information we hold about you, and details about how we are processing your personal information;

2\. to have any inaccuracies in your personal information corrected;

3\. if we are processing your personal information by automated means and on the basis of your consent (see “How do we use it?”, above), for us to provide your personal information to you in a structured, commonly-used and machine-readable format. You can also ask us to provide your personal information directly to a third party in this format, and, if technically feasible, we will do so; and

4\. to have your personal information erased, or for our use of it to be restricted (for example, if your preferences change, or if you don’t want us to send you the information you have requested).

Please contact us using the details set out below if you would like to exercise any of these rights.

You also have the right to make a complaint to the supervisory authority if you’re not happy with how we’ve handled your personal information. In the UK, the supervisory authority is the Information Commissioner’s Office ([http://www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)).

**Responsible Disclosures  
  
**VML appreciates and values the identification and reporting of security vulnerabilities carried out by well-intentioned, ethical security researchers. Please read our [Responsible Disclosures Policy](https://www.vml.com/responsible-disclosure) in full.  

**Privacy Policy in Japan  
**Please click [this link](https://www.vml.com/privacy-policy-japan) for further information with regard to the Privacy Policy in Japan.

**California Residents**  
  
If you are a California resident, if you need additional information and rights that may apply to you as an employee, applicant or contractor click [here](https://www.vml.com/ccpa-policy), for such that may apply to you as a client click [here](https://www.wundermanthompson.com/client-privacy-policy) or for such that may apply to you as a supplier click [here](https://www.wundermanthompson.com/suppliers-privacy-policy).  

**How to contact us**

If you wish to exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information or if you have any queries about how we use your personal information, please let us know by contacting us at the following address: Wunderman Thompson LLC d/b/a VML, 175 Greenwich Street, Floor 16, New York, NY 10007  
United States or by email at [dpo@vml.com](mailto:dpo@vml.com)

**Changes to this privacy policy**

We review this privacy policy on a regular basis to ensure that it is up-to-date with our use of your personal information, and compliant with applicable data protection laws.

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to revise this privacy policy at any time. The updated privacy policy will be posted on our website. You are encouraged to review this privacy policy from time to time.

* Cookie Settings

Connect with us

### © 2024 VML. A [WPP Company](https://www.wpp.com/).
